RACHEL DANIEL

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER | NASHVILLE, TN

ABOUT ME

As I began my post-college job-hunt, armed with a BFA in Theater and a Minor in Accounting, I knew only two things:

First, as much as I loved the beauty of art and numbers, neither path felt quite right as an ultimate career choice; and second, my primary goal was to find a job with the right blend of creativity and critical thinking.

I was first introduced to the world of Software Development as a Systems Operations Analyst at Community Health Systems, where I worked alongside Developers, gathering data about system use for our department.

When I stepped into the role of Systems Operations Manager and became the liaison between our department's tech staff and our hundreds of application users, I realized I loved being a part of the creation and improvement of technology with the end user always in mind. More than anything I enjoyed diving into the code to search for answers any time I was asked the age-old question-- is this issue a bug, user error, or intentional design upon which we can improve?

Ultimately it became clear that Software Development was the rigorous, creative and exciting career for which I'd been searching. I decided to part ways with the company that had grown me into a professional, and enrolled in Nashville Software School's Full-Time Web Developer Bootcamp.

I couldn't be more excited to be learning Full-Stack Development (Python/Django backend) with NSS' Cohort 28, and can't wait to see what comes next.

EMPLOYMENT

Nashville Software School

Full-Stack Developer | Oct 2018 - Present

NSS is a Tennessee Non-Profit corporation providing intensive training, mentorship and apprenticeship in order to prepare students for an entry level software developer job creating web sites, applications and/or mobile apps.

Community Health Systems

Systems Operations Manager | Dec 2017 - Sept 2018 Senior Operations Analyst | Jan 2015 - Dec 2017 Operations Analyst | Apr 2011 - Jan 2015 Call Center Representative | Aug 2010 - Mar 2011 Assistant to the Financial Advisor | May 2009 - Aug 2009

CHS is a Fortune 500 company and provider of general hospital services in the US. My 8+ years with CHS were spent working for the Eligibility Screening Services department, which specializes in locating federal, state and/or county programs to cover the medical bills of uninsured patients of CHS hospitals.

EDUCATION

Nashville Software School

Full-Stack Developer | Oct 2018 - Present
Six Month Bootcamp for Full-Stack Web Development (back end Python/Django)

University of Mississippi

Bachelor of Fine Arts
Theatre Arts, Minor in Accounting

TECH EXPERIENCE

- Managed a team of six analysts who in turn handled departmental equipment distribution, technical support, security/access, reporting and data analytics
- Served as first point of contact for department leadership for troubleshooting in Artiva (Ontario Systems) as well as Enhancement Requests for Artiva. This necessitated reviewing scripts and tactics written by the Developers on a regular basis.
- Attended and contributed to weekly Enhancement Meetings with the Director of Sys Ops and the Artiva Developers
- Constructed ad hoc reports for department leadership using SQL and Crystal Reports
- For four months, while the Director of Systems Operations was on maternity leave, I temporarily managed the Artiva Developers. During that time, I oversaw all day-to-day departmental operations including acquisitions, divestitures and host system conversions. I also oversaw development projects and tested new programming before weekly deployment.

CONTACT INFO:

Mobile: (615) 598-0659

Email: rachdaniel88@gmail.com

LinkedIn:.linkedin.com/in/rachel-daniel-

nashville/

GitHub: github.com/racheldaniel

SKILLS/TECHNOLOGIES

• HTML

 Browserify Grunt

CSS

Bootstrap

• JavaScript ES6 • SQL

 ReactStrap Materialize

• React • NPM

¡Query

PROJECTS

GiftStorm: The Brainstorming App for Gift-Giving

NSS Front-End Capstone Project

As someone with a large immediate family, birthdays, anniversaries and other celebrations seem to sneak up on me on a monthly basis, leaving me not only giftless, but idea-less.

To put an end to last-minute holiday scrambling, I created GiftStorm -- a React App that allows users to track interests, gift ideas, purchases and upcoming holidays for all of their friends in one, easy-to-use interface.

Using a local ISON database, the app stores all user-specific data, allowing unique experiences depending on the logged-in user. The app features full CRUD functionality, so users can add, update and delete interests, ideas and purchases, as well as what holidays they are tracking, allowing the user to brainstorm freely and spontaneously.

GiftStorm uses Moment.js to display the closest upcoming celebrations to the user along with the status of their gift purchasing for that occasion.

The app is simple and user-friendly, styled with ReactStrap and Bootstrap CSS frameworks.

github.com/racheldaniel/Gift-Storm/